<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PROJECT_SET>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB41376" alias="ena-STUDY-Key Laboratory of Environmental and Applied Microbiology, CAS-17-11-2020-03:39:55:672-474" center_name="Key Laboratory of Environmental and Applied Microbiology, CAS">
     <IDENTIFIERS>
          <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB41376</PRIMARY_ID>
          <SECONDARY_ID>ERP125143</SECONDARY_ID>
          <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Key Laboratory of Environmental and Applied Microbiology, CAS">ena-STUDY-Key Laboratory of Environmental and Applied Microbiology, CAS-17-11-2020-03:39:55:672-474</SUBMITTER_ID>
     </IDENTIFIERS>
     <NAME>microbial diversity of human skin</NAME>
     <TITLE>microbial diversity of human skin</TITLE>
     <DESCRIPTION>Human skin microorganisms play a certain role in human health, but also affected by many environmental factors or host factors. However, few researchers have studied the variation of skin microbiota in different body sites of people from two countries in the same environment. Here, with the support of 16S rRNA sequencing technology, we studied the diversity and function of skin microbiome in different parts of Chinese and Pakistani people in a single college. Body location was the most significant factor affecting community structure, followed by country. Due to different living habits and genetic characteristics of the host, Proteobacteria is more abundant in Pakistanis than in Chinese. At the genus level, Prevotella, Deinococcus and Staphylococcus are rich in Chinese samples. There were significant differences in Shannon diversity of skin microorganisms in different body parts of Chinese, but not in Pakistan. In addition, bacterial communities on the forehead and cheek of Chinese and Pakistanis were significantly separated. Staphylococcus is the core genus of cutaneous bacterial with the highest average relative abundance. In the functional prediction, the carbohydrate metabolism, lipid metabolism, and xenobiotics biodegradation and metabolism function in Pakistan is higher than that in China, but the amino acid metabolism of skin microorganism in Chinese is higher. There may be different pathogenic microorganisms in different parts of human body, which has great enlightenment for the study of disease transmission and public health. Through the meta-analysis of skin samples from eight altitudes, it was found that the diversity first decreased and then increased with the increase of altitude. Network analysis showed that there were positive correlation among Lactobacillus, Chryseobacterium, Acinetobacter and altitude. Our results analyzed the variation of skin microbiota and its significance for human health from the perspective of cutaneous bacterial in both countries.</DESCRIPTION>
     <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
          <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
     </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
     <PROJECT_LINKS>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
                    <ID>ERA3145805</ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
                    <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB41376&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
                    <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB41376&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
     </PROJECT_LINKS>
     <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
          <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
               <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
               <VALUE>2022-01-30</VALUE>
          </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
          <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
               <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
               <VALUE>2022-01-30</VALUE>
          </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
     </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
</PROJECT_SET>
