<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PROJECT_SET>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB41619" alias="ena-STUDY-YALE-30-11-2020-17:29:05:684-46" center_name="Yale University, New Haven, United States">
     <IDENTIFIERS>
          <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB41619</PRIMARY_ID>
          <SECONDARY_ID>ERP125422</SECONDARY_ID>
          <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Yale University, New Haven, United States">ena-STUDY-YALE-30-11-2020-17:29:05:684-46</SUBMITTER_ID>
     </IDENTIFIERS>
     <NAME>Malignant T Cell Activation by Bacillus safensis isolated from Cutaneous T Cell Lymphoma Lesions</NAME>
     <TITLE>MALIGNANT T CELL ACTIVATION BY A BACILLUS SPECIES ISOLATED FROM CUTANEOUS T CELL LYMPHOMA LESIONS</TITLE>
     <DESCRIPTION>Cutaneous T cell lymphoma (CTCL is a life-debilitating malignancy of lymphocytes homing to the skin. While CTCL is thought to arise from a combination of genetic, epigenetic and environmental factors, specific triggers are unclear. 
The skin is colonized by a unique microbiota and is heavily influenced by its interactions. We hypothesized that adaptive immune responses to skin commensals leads to clonal T cell proliferation and transformation in the appropriate genetic background. We therefore collected lesional and non-lesional skin microbiota from CTCL patients to study T cell interactions using skin T cell explants and peripheral, skin-homing CD4+ T cells. 
By various methods, we identified Bacillus safensis in CTCL lesions, a rare human commensal in healthy skin, and demonstrated it can induce malignant T cell activation and cytokine secretion. Taken together, our data suggest microbial triggers in the skin microbiota of CTCL patients as potential instigators of tumorigenesis.</DESCRIPTION>
     <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
          <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
     </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
     <PROJECT_LINKS>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
                    <ID>ERA3179125</ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
                    <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB41619&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
          <PROJECT_LINK>
               <XREF_LINK>
                    <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
                    <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB41619&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
               </XREF_LINK>
          </PROJECT_LINK>
     </PROJECT_LINKS>
     <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
          <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
               <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
               <VALUE>2021-09-27</VALUE>
          </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
          <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
               <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
               <VALUE>2021-09-29</VALUE>
          </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
     </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
</PROJECT_SET>
